[Music]
welcome to raina's show this is the
podcast where I interview entrepreneurs
and Mavericks who gets
done hey hey what's up my friend so
today we have Elson 2 on the show so
Elson is an independent Trader and one
of the leading instructors at piran
profits so what's interesting about is
that he used to be an ex proprietary
Trader and to dat right he has earned
over
6.5 million US dollars right throughout
his trading career trading Forex Futures
stocks and even crypto so if you want to
you know connect more with Elson right
I'll put his uh details in the
description below moving on in today's
episode you will learn number one what
is proprietary trading and how does it
work number two how why did Elson turned
down a six figure salary job to become a
proprietary Trader then we talk about
how the markets have changed over the
years we talk about elen's price action
manipulation strategy that allows him to
profit in Bull and bare markets and this
is the same strategy that he used to
trade Forex stocks and even the crypto
markets then we spoke about how he spots
opportunities in the crypto markets that
allowed him right to 10x his money then
we also talk about how he became an
instructor at piran profits and much
more so all this in today's episode go
listen to it right
[Music]
now all right Elson welcome to the show
thanks vaa for having me happy to have
you Elson so to kick things off right
you have made no Millions as a
proprietary Trader so I think people are
now wondering what is proprietary
trading all right uh I believe you you
also know about propra trading because
you were there before so Pro trading
basically means that uh uh we trade the
firm's Capital right we don't really
have like a hash funds uh take
management fee from investors so the
capital that was uh funded by the the
the boss or the company and then we
trade and to to generate uh net profits
from from the capital that we were given
yeah be trading in in Forex futures or
stocks and during my time I trade more
on uh Futures my first five years in the
prop Des yeah then I get a p payout of
the the profits so I'm guessing because
different F different Arrangement do you
do they pay like a monthly like a small
allowance or is just zero dollar just
profit share purely I was in fact I was
lucky when during the time when I join
like I have this my my package was 50/50
of the net profit so there wasn't any
basic pay except for the first three
months there was this $500 like
probation uh allowance they call
allowance and then the profit sharing is
20% Then after the first two months is
purely 50/50 and then there's no basic
basic pay so when you say you just
joined prop trading do you have any
experience trading or you came in like
brand new I did uh attended some uh
trading courses before in fact one of
the course I attended is by conr uh con
Elvin Lim uh who also uh train under
Adam during that time so that that cost
actually spuck my interest in in trading
thank giv me a very good background to
get to get started but I always know
that I need something more than just uh
the trading cost I need to be there to
see how the the real the so called the
real Traders trade because I know that
certain things you can learn from the
books but things like how do you handle
emotions every day how what how what do
they do when they're in profits what do
they do when they in the loss do they
average in or do they cut and how do
they reenter of course strategy is
important
but I think the psychological part of
how people handle emotions day and day
is also as important for a Trader so
that's the reason why I think it's
important to join the prop desk when I
was given the opportunity so I think
speaking of opportunity I read I think
from Adam if I'm not wrong he said that
you know I think on one of his tweet
said you actually turned down a six
figure salary job with a top Bank to
become a proprietary Trader so what what
was running through your mind when you
made that decision so before I graduate
uh I actually studed business it so
naturally I should go into a it line and
during the time I was being offered some
role with the bank one of the top Banks
uh it's very natural for fresh gr to
actually get a job before they graduate
maybe during my time like my my I was
from SMU so a lot of us got offers
before we
graduate
and during the time and before that I
actually uh went to for
internship right at one of the top US
Bank as well and then for that six
months when I was there as an intern
right I've seen I I sort of experien how
is it like being a full-time employee in
the bank and just before I left I
remember my former boss actually told me
this I did ask him like before I left
actually I was being offered this should
I come back or should I go for a trading
rle and he didn't actually give me a
straight answer but that was doing after
the financial crisis in 20 or 2010 and
he told me this like I still remember
this very clear they told me this one
day when I asked him for and you say
that if you are good don't come back I
was I was shocked with about uh about
his reply and then he he told me that if
you come back this is what you see you
will become like me in the next few
years he's the Vice President in the
bank and of course he has a lot of
certain uh Untold gces right he had
shared with me before when he was
working in the bank so he he told me
that if you if you have a different if
you have interest in certain things go
for it when you are young you can make
the mistakes when you are young go for
your passion and then I did ask myself
like why am I very passionate about and
when I do my research and I realized
that at that point of time right not a
lot of prop firms are hiring and I was
very honored to be hired by my former
boss he actually gave me a
chance and during the time when I when I
go for interview he actually told me
that he's going to hire about five
people only and then like uh from SMU is
only two three is from other university
and then I happen to know oh if you're
going to only hire two from let's say my
University there's like probably
hundreds or even thousands of people
applying do I want to give this
opportunity up will I be able to find
back this role in the prop desk and I
ask myself that if I can get into the
bank now maybe three years down the road
if I really need to go into a bank I can
still go to the bank and actually my
former boss also told me this like like
before I left just go for a passion like
if you really like trading just go for
it right and if you really die that you
didn't make it come and find me in a few
years down the road I
will just look for me and I will I will
get you something so that was the
assurance that he gave me and I thought
about it for next few days and
eventually I decided to uh join the prop
t Okay so let's talk bit about the
interview because my interview process
was pretty interesting back then as as a
prop Trader so what was your interview
process like as a prop Trader I think
the typical questions uh like they will
ask you do you have any experience have
you traded
before how do you handle
stress but one of the key thing I think
I was being asked like what's my what's
the trigger that I want
to why why do I want to uh do trading
and my answer was very Frank during the
time I don't know whether it's a ker or
break like is a break a deal breaker
deal breaker right that I just say to
make money because during time my family
was having some financial hardship my
dad was going through uh some bankruptcy
fing and I just knew in my mind I need
to make money faster right I need to be
sustainable then that was the the thing
I just told my interviewer I said that I
I'm I have nothing to lose and I'm
willing to give my all for the for the
the job yeah and I told him that I I I
actually got offer but I still want to
go into to this this role it's like
between a six figure salary offer and
something that pays you a few hundred a
month with profit sharing it's more
uncertain you chose the uncertain one
right because I think without the family
hardship I would not have chosen this
path I would be probably thought that
when you are stable you want more
stability but when you are a bit
unstable you don't mind anyway is really
unstable so why not go for that
uncertainty so I guess that was the my
mindset during that time okay be ironic
think I need the money now I better take
something stable to quickly pay back
whatever difficulties Finance I'm facing
but but apparently your train of thought
was more since unstable let's you know
maybe unstability really make you feel
uncom comfortable with this uncertainty
I'm not sure if that played part yes I
think that also my character like all my
my like my my parents my uncles all them
are considered businessmen you in fact
my sis is my sis my brother all them are
not uh working as employee all them are
like
freelancer
Trader so my environment when I grow up
is you can say a lot of us is not like
salary
mindset I I see my father going through
all the ups and downs despite the downs
I still see his vager to continue so I I
I my this kind of like his resilience so
when I naturally given a choice between
a something that's stable and something
that I can see I can make a lot of money
and uh work for myself right I and it's
something I'm passionate about I should
go for that power okay so I from what I
know so trading you know there's a
learning curve involved most people they
take like a few years to to become
profitable so for you like you know when
you started with the Prof you know how
long did it take for you to know kind of
like grind it out figure things out
before you know you had your first
paycheck well I say that uh okay I still
remember my my my first quarter I made
about 9,000 so I did have some
background in trading I told you I
attended some uh trading course so there
are some I have some background about
risk management but one of the things
that really what I what has really
helped me doing the in the prop Des is
that uh I learned about consistency and
risk management in fact when I first
joined right I remember my my boss
actually told us this when I first
joined I don't care what you do every
day you do five trades round trips Buy
sell Buy sell Buy sell Buy sell byy sell
because set up no setup you do five
trades and each trade you
R uh $2 $300 that means your limit per
day is about a thousand then you are out
you'll be surprised on this simple Ru
not many people can follow means they
have they over trade they under trade or
they blow up
first Sometimes they they they when
something go against them they will say
oh they might have wa I don't cut first
I then the thing go lower then say mind
I don't I don't I don't cut first they
will come back I never come back
or sometimes they they think that oh
just because it's come back right then
next time they don't they don't cut they
say oh see every time I cut they go back
then next time I don't cut so a lot of
psychological play uh among themsel I
mean on the Traer part and yeah then you
say do five five round trips like some
people may do just one then you ask them
why they see no opportunity but the
instruction is very clear do five round
trips got sell no sell do five round
trips then then some people ask then is
it like I just anyhow click yeah even if
you have to anyhow click but the thing
is that uh you need to have a basis
certain basis can also cannot really
anyhow click like your business can be
like maybe the price that support right
then hit resistance sell maybe the price
hit moving average 20
50 100 SMA 200 SMA then there must be
certain basis so there's no exact
strategy that we were taught that was
the first thing I learned and he
actually teach me a very valuable lesson
that even if you are given a clear
instruction right not many people can
follow and you have to despite all the
noise out there you must be the one that
follow the
rules what was your ex boss kind of like
the mindset when he gave you this
instruction what was he trying to see
when he gave you the set of
instructions after this exercise this
exercise lasted about a week right then
he actually told us that it's not about
making making money it's to train you to
listen to instruction oh okay so you see
whether you can follow instructions can
follow instructions in fact every day we
doing the first week we have a debrief
every day and then we talk about he why
yesterday you only do three trades and
why you cut more than you were supposed
to so there's a lot of key lessons in
that one week and subsequently I think
the second week we do the same thing but
uh we
improve yeah because during the time we
trade we trade based on the letters the
you know the trading letter so you don't
really put a stop loss yourself of
course you cannot using new using the
trading Technologies I believe you use
that as well uh you can put your stop
loss automated stop loss but most of the
time uh in the prop Des we professional
we cut ourself so when the thing come
you must click but most people don't
there to click yeah so by the way what
Elon is referring to the letter is they
we call it a depth of Market where you
can see the beats and offers in real
time on the Futures exchange I think
believe that's what you're trading back
then okay so apparently your first three
month a form of structure in terms of
education on how to actually progress as
as a Trader back then for you there's no
really like formal C but there was like
uh learn learning points every day so
there will be debrief every day uh and
then some guidance on like strategy like
what should you do when you see this
kind
scenario so we trade many different
types of strategy like directional
spreads so even in Direction know
there's other things that you need to
know like your technicals must be Tip
Top Of course just the simple things
that you need to understand was 2050 SMA
there like a given then you need to know
your support resistance and then when
you go deeper will be like all the
manipulation signals like uh buot trap
bad trap why is it that he must go down
first before he go up don't take things
at face value just because the news is
bullish data bullish you buy then die
you see so there are a lot these kind of
things we go deeper and then there will
be spreads how to do a spread how to L A
good
spread yeah so that was how I we we get
started the first month learning about
technical this year Al so this one they
kind teach you all this different
overview of this different strategies
that you can employ but they can only I
guess cover the basic after that you
have to go into the trenes and figure
all the nuances yourself as a Trader so
back then as a prop Trader what was some
of the strategies that you employ back
then when you were trading I think
mainly I
when I joined 20 2010 2011 the the ELO
start to become more
blatant right more obvious more more
active yeah more active from 2006 2007
is there less less crazy backr right I I
was told that before I join right the it
was very easy to make money that's what
I heard as
well okay I think uh yeah when I join
it's like the the the ELO start to be
more and more blatant and obvious and
catch a lot scalpers right it's not e as
easy to scalp as before that's why to
overcome it my boss always say you must
have the Train the stock to do position
trading okay Lo basically holding your
trade for longer dur situation to
overcome the shortterm noise and being
caught by the elos so that was when I
knew that you need to adapt to the
market any always te these are like
every era has a hero what works last
time not work today but in today's
market there will be a a a set of Heroes
that will be able to unlock the market
so don't live in the past like you
missed opportunity last time the
sculping market last time the easy way
of just buy and sell off the screen is
over just like the bit when they when
they traded right when transit to
electronic you need to you need to know
what's the rules and then you as a gamer
or so on you must know what's the rules
and overcome it so how did you mentioned
the ELO more blat how did that affect
your sculping or your trading back then
when you're doing to low time frame like
five minutes and lower right and you are
looking at the order dep to to see like
the bit RS and then you try to scalp the
the shter movement right it get more and
more lat in a way that there was a lot
of
spoofing right spoofing means the the so
called the market maker by the way
market maker control more than 90% of
the the beat and R you Market all of us
who know this in the proest so what they
do is and they are the only one who is
has the ability to spoof
legally right so they can actually Bluff
you let's say the market is moving up
and then they are ready to come down
what they can do is they can actually
put a bit a big big size to BL people
that hey a big orders is coming in then
when everyone keep buying right and the
chart is green then people see the bit
is very heavy let say there's 5,000 lot
versus 500 on the offer naturally people
think hey what uh a lot of buyers coming
let's go and hit the offer right then
the market is green candle so that was
when actually this is like example of
trick that they try to absorb this the
the liquidity I mean to become sell
liquidity but they are actually
refreshing the office we call it Iceberg
like some of us know that Iceberg then
they just keep refilling and then when
they done they'll do a chrome that means
suddenly once they done the 500 5,000
lot will disappear and then the market
will do a blip to catch all the scalpers
so this happens very often every day
then sometimes you don't know whether
it's real or fake because sometimes it
could be real so right some could be
real yes some oh uh we say paper order
come in paper order means the
institution order means usually they
want to get fi at what at whatever price
they
want you see people coming in hey what
disappear
job so it get more and more blatant like
last time my people come they will
really push they can follow but when
when I join the time I think things
really
get like you can't really read off such
a signal anymore it can be fake that's
when you need I was told to adapt and do
more uh position trade even when you
scop you you or you do a spread you L it
in a way that you are positioning you
look at the chart to L the buy side
first right and then you see that if you
hit the bearish pattern then you L the
sell side so we use you need to use that
sense Market sense and or skill right to
overcome the out gos to survive so for
you you're using both a combination of
the the depth of Market charts and other
technicals and not just the the letter
itself yeah you can't do that anymore
okay because back then my my early days
I think some firms where they were a
huge proponents of letter you just look
at the letter no chart so they force
them to just look at letter and I guess
to adap market conditions change okay so
what are some of the challenges you you
faced as a prop Trader back then I think
the biggest challenge is the emotion
part dayto day every sometimes you can
uh I I've gone through things like days
where I first three days I make money I
can lose it back in one day or two weeks
I make money I can lose it in just like
15 minutes I gone through such period
and then that's when I question myself
why am I doing this and especially when
I give up a quite a a good full-time job
to join pop trading and then my peers
who are in let's say Investment Banking
they are like earning big bucks and like
no they're not taking risk as long as
they're there they get paid every month
but I need to every day sit there and
engage think about how to fight the
market so that that was the tough part I
have to always tell myself like think of
a long term like some when I like first
few first two quarters I didn't make
more than my target is 10,000 I mean
that's what all of us join for you need
I think you need to minimum make at
least 10K so when I join I make like
9,000 for the first quarter so that was
like 3K a month and I was quite upset I
was like w my f are making like easily
67,000 outside and I'm I I I spend 16
hours a day
I go through all the emotion I'm making
3,000 that was the tough part then you
don't see the light at the end of T you
need to keep persevere even though you
don't see any light yeah that that was
how I did the tough part I guess so what
was the CU I can really what you mean by
you know two weeks of gains then within
like short per time everything got
because of human mistakes or error so
what was like your train of thought to
kind of like tell yourself to keep on
going and not leave prop trading for
another job what was you know the
thoughts in your head
I I see the long term and I try to talk
to other Traders I think having a
community of Traders is important then I
talk to them how do we handle emotions I
talk to my boss and hear some of their
stories some of sometimes these kind of
stories become your your winning speech
right when you
succeed sometimes this okay so when you
want to inspire others you can use this
story as like a motivation for yeah okay
so I remember my my okay my former boss
he told me he joined the simx as a as a
pit Trader right so I think when I think
I have a losing Street and one day I
asked him how do you manage then he told
me this story then I still remember it
still
today one for the first year when he was
in simx he before he joined simx he
actually saw his friend making money so
he actually wanted to join them as well
so he sold his house I remember he told
us this he sold his house hdb I think
somewhere in Woodlands or B and after he
sell house put a family into a rental
apartment and then he use the money go
and trade in simx for first one year
right after he sold the house the
property price keep going up he also I
think he was very stressed and then uh
also that one year he don't have to
really trade because he was Rand new and
then he see all the people like shouting
like then he don't have to follow them
all thing then first year he didn't make
money he still was so quite depressed
until actually told me that he was at
the Singapore River there sitting down
there and asking himself why why is he
doing this you know like he can't buy
back the house because prices gone up
after the first year he he he I think he
told me that he things have to change he
need to do something justic so I think
the second year he actually follow the
big Traders and he tried to uh mimic the
way they trade and take action then
second year onwards things start to
improve and of course uh long story
short he's one of the top Trader Legend
in in simx bought instead of uh buying
back the same hdb he bought bought back
the Ed so that was like motivating story
motivating story so so you when you
compare this kind of story and you ask
yourself yeah why is my daily loss like
that one two weeks this nothing as a
Trader you need to persevere see keep
doing the right thing I always tell
myself like even if I lose money right
but if I know that I'm doing the right
thing right I don't care what people say
I will just continue because sometime
you can get affected by your peers or
friends or family you like to actually
ask you to stop
yeah so how do you know what is the
right thing despite losing money I think
like I say speak to Traders like
sometime I if I have a draw down I I was
talk to Traders talk to senior Traders
my boss and I ask them like if you were
me will you do the same right what would
you do in this kind of situation I
always I like to ask them this kind of
thing is it like pertaining to like a
trading scenario or trading scenario
training scenario okay like like those
traders who make money I always ask them
like how
when everyone is losing money why are
you making money what are you doing
differently and they're willing to to
share I guess your your colleagues yes I
think that's a good part about in the
community we we do
share uh then we learn from each other
why he doing the yeah just now the price
action I shouldn't do this I should
follow him I Mar I cannot keep shoting
he's the only guy longing and I need to
ask him like why what makes you long you
keep asking question and then you you
learn from that and if you find that hey
every what these good Traders are saying
are all yeah all the same right then
even if you lose money and they also
lose money I know that I'm doing right
thing ah okay might they come to a point
where because the market is is not very
big then if you guys go certain amount
of size you guys start competing each
other for for liquidity you know such
scenario that uh does happen especially
as the year goes by the liquidity start
to drop it came to the point where
sometimes there's some tension like when
we do spread right right if I want to
sell then some some of my CL may think
that I'm pushing down the market I got
that what uh before that I always say
that the market is dynamic if someone
thinks that what is the price that I
sell right is too low someone will
buy so we cannot because I I scar that
you I SC I'm going to push on the market
for everyone then I don't have to sell
you see then what if I cut loss Will
everyone take my loss so if you know
that that the liquidity is poor then you
the trader have to make the Judgment
call whether to even go in in the first
place like if all of us know that all of
us go in the liquidity is poor then all
of us must decide whether you yourself
want to go in knowing that a lot of us
may go into the same trade because
sometimes you can be have like a meta
game where let's say liquidity is poor
you're of larger size you know how your
CCT is going to think right you can
actually cause the market to behave in a
certain way such they think along those
lines they make certain actions and they
profit from their losses because kind of
Zero Sum right so that's how I guess
tension would really come about you know
yes uh but I would say sometimes because
we we individual book sorry individual
book okay your p&l is individual is not
group so yeah that kind of tension do
happen like if you sell then the thing
really come down the person still
holding there of course he would think
that you are the one who push the market
down would they know that like say you
Elson you CA it or it's more like
Anonymous okay generally is supposed to
be
anonymous like my traits my colleag
should not know but because he very
open right and usually you person on
left and right will know what you're
doing on so that's why in the prop desk
the corner seat is the best nobody can
see what yeah the corner then as the
best is the corner and nobody
see yeah and if I'm not wrong it's a
prop Traer you have death fees to pay as
well right yeah yeah yeah what was your
your cost per month back then if I'm not
wrong one month is about I remember I
paid 9,000 per quarter okay 9,000 so
about 3K Sing Sing
doll yes okay was that amount you pay
also I pay about 2,000,000 plus of 2K I
think yeah depending on what what
software to using TT Pro is very
expensive I think may I using light I
can't I was using back but I think not
more than not more than 2K on my side
the funny thing is when we were using TD
Pro but we were not using most of the
function just using the order the
Lether yeah okay so I mean ear you also
mentioned that the markets have actually
changed quite a bit over over the years
right so so let's say from the the time
you join prop trading then maybe now is
at what a good 15 years later how how
would you say the market has has changed
over time ELO definitely comes in uh in
a big way and then is the your age right
on the lower time frame especially less
than 15 minutes is being eroded to a
very high extent in my view meaning that
the price action on the lower term just
a lot more choppy a lot more choppy okay
yeah so the higher time frame will go
the safer you get the age still preval
on high time frame so that's the reason
why in even if I scalp I do at least 30
minutes at least 30 minutes and then uh
I do more of like swing trade when you
say Scot means you close within the day
itself like day trading yeah if I do 30
minutes or 1 hour you usually will be
done within 24 hours okay so can but
know how do you then trade the markets
today so back then you were you know
sculping and doing a few other things
but what about now today how do you
approach the markets I do a combination
of both sculping uh and also uh swing
trading and because of Lifestyle reasons
I I don't want to sit there uh the whole
day like doing shortterm trading because
if you do shortterm you need to be there
so I do more like swing trading on the
high time frame example the weekly chart
but to compensate for the low frequency
I do a bigger
size if I see a very good set I may go
in a big in a big way when you big is it
like like percentage of capital is on
the higher end of the percentage yes
okay like normal trades I reach between
1 to 2% of my portfolio and then if I
really got conviction on certain things
I may go like 10
20% so what are some of the things that
gives you more conviction over the other
setups uh okay example if if the stock
is previously a very hype up stock hype
up mean like now maybe
Nvidia and meta this kind of type of
stocks probably if they drop like a few
years ago like it was plena and Tesla a
few years back then it was very hype up
and then it came crashing down and after
I do a a bullish signal so I knew that
you know some certain stocks when
previously they were have a hyp up and
then if the fundamental is do there and
after retracing for 80% or even 90%
right the chance of a multi is very high
because all need to do is just be to go
back to the back to the 30% mark from
the bottom right is 100% one bger yeah
so these are the times when usually I
will go in a little bit
bigger right and then go for that and I
try to identify this opportunity once a
while to boost my my uh
portfolio and this executed on the the
weekly time frame weekly time frame
which is more reliable especially for
swing trade in my view okay okay maybe
to dive in a little bit deeper let's say
whatever stock stock we talking B he
dropped 90% from the high so now it's
just from $100 to $10 and let's say now
has recovered to about 20 over Okay so
let's say walking through that setup at
Point at $10 what are the specific thing
that you look for on the charts before
you enter a long trade of Pena okay so
my main strategy that employ is called
price action manipulation so look out
for in generic terms uh things like bull
trap and be
traps of course I have different like uh
special criteria but to keep it simple
generic form is bull traps and be traps
so for palen I think back a few years
ago when it was around $7 plus right
there was a bad trap so bad trap
basically means that example this a
support the price break below support So
price break below support doesn't may
seem like a just to cause people to sell
but actually it could be a sign that the
market the big boys on market makers are
actually trying to accumulate take out
the stop loss because stop losses that
beinging place there by the people who
are long are usually sell orders and
who's absorbing the sell orders the
market makers will be absorbing if
someone trigger the below the support so
when I saw that in on the higher time
frame for benter right and especially
dropped like almost 70 80% I told myself
that there's a good chance right that
the so called the big boys are
accumulating the position
so on that basis I actually measure my
re and I see my is quite low versus the
100% Mark $7 to $14 $15 I think the re
is like one is to three or
four right and I told myself is a it's a
decent trade setup so I'm just going to
try to paint the visualization pictures
just to make sure I understand correctly
so let's say p goes up to a high of $100
it make goes to a 90% draw down to $10
for that uh be trap to occur it needs to
go into maybe kind of a range we
consolidate so they can take out the
lows of that the recent lows and then if
there's a b trap you look to to go long
correct okay then where would you then
typically you know set your stops and
Target I usually put it at the immediate
swing low okay so just before the low of
the bar trap they just so let's say a
support the price goes down and goes
back up then I put it just below where
it last visited that that level there
then I measure my entry stop loss then
project okay then take profit Target
usually I like to
for this kind of trade I like to exit
based on discretion so discretion means
I don't just put a take profit like once
to do I just put it there because I find
that when in when I'm doing this kind of
trade I don't want to Short Change
Myself what if it can go higher I want
to see the potential so I will wait for
it to move until maybe you hit a
resistance or you do a what we call a
flush it mean a big green bars that's
where I would look to sell okay and
sometimes even though these two scenario
occur I may not not sell
because I if if if has not if the stock
have not recovered 100% I will not sell
when you say recover 100% are you
refering to the alltime high that was
being made or 100% from the lows or from
the lows CU When drop 80 90% right like
let's say this low is $7 I'll tell
myself since this is the 89% low if I'm
bre and it rebounds it should go to 14
100% okay it's the same mental model I
have for crypto a lot of times a lot
crypto like now a lot crypto drop 80 90%
And when they if I'm long I'm not going
to take 50% because if I'm right that
this is the bottom they should three 5x
at least from the price you entered then
around the three to 5x zone right I'll
look out for resistance level then I'll
look up I'll draw my lines there and I
look out for exit over there okay like
if the line is at 50% Mark I will ignore
that line basically that that that's
what I meant okay and does like volume
take do you take into account volume
when you you know trading in this manner
okay volume is like initial screener
right volume will affect the liquidity
of the stock so I like to go for stocks
where they have at least 100K average
volume so that know you know that like
there's interaction between the the
market makers and the retailers right
and usually this will affect the B
spread if the liquidity is like say less
than 100K right usually the be spread
you'll see that it's bit white more than
5 10 5% which is is not very good
usually usually want to keep it below 3%
so for this setup you sh I can imagine
that it can actually be used in many
different situation like the one you
just Shar is the stock price having like
a 80 90% draw down alternatively I'm
thinking you can even use it as a
counter Trend tra where stock price
retest maybe the all-time highs and then
gives you like a a bull trap for example
or maybe a stock is trending up higher
it goes into the range you can have
another B TR while is trending up so I
guess there's many different scenarios
where this particular strategy that you
just sh can be employed right depending
on the market conditions or or the stock
that you want to trade correct so this
yeah so this is one type I of of so-call
scenarios I like because this is when I
can go for multi bags okay this like so
my my ideal multibag scenario of course
I cannot just wait for you know when you
catch fish you cannot you CH the net you
cannot just say I only want that fish so
you CH the net you will have many other
fish on the net so I also look got for
other kind of scenar was like the normal
continuation trade buy high sell higher
CU you don't always expect things to
always drop 80% away for you sometime
when Market is in a fullblown Bo run
like currently right now in the kind of
like 80% draw down and then we bottom up
scenario get lesser and lesser so it's
like also a season when the market is
retrace retrace then you have a lot of
discount scenarios when Market is in
ongoing bu run you will have to stick to
the buy high sell higher kind of setup
all right okay let me back to to prop
trading our wanting to ask this question
because I myself I know having left the
industry I've SE quite a number of
traders who actually quit trading all
together some maybe even become taxi
driver I was wondering do you see
something similar at at your end when I
was in in the pop desk yeah like you
know people just leave trading all all
together they don't trade
anymore uh yes in fact I think most of
us still go into this line like trading
or investing okay so in finance related
in finance related just that whether you
are the execution Ro
so uh for me I I would say being a trade
if you leave the prop des and you become
independent Trader you are still a very
direct execution rule some of them
became uh order execution yeah EX order
execution role in the bank that means
they they take orders they take
instruction then they execute they don't
take proprietary trading kind of R and
another type is they just Pur do risk
management I friends who uh
colleagues uh before they left I ask
them what are you going to what are you
going to do they told me I'm going to do
risk management in the
bank and what's the reason I'm tired of
taking
risk so you TI of taking R you want to
do risk management so risk management
and trading is two different thing right
it's not even related to trading anymore
I think it's not you can see somehow it
is also related I mean you help the bank
to control RIS but you're not taking
risk anymore okay when you a Trader you
you control risk and you're taking risk
M okay so yeah uh this be interesting
one so again this a tweet that I I read
from Adam right he say along the lines
of you know he left the firm to trade
his own money right so since then he has
made over 6.5 million Us in trading
profits uh trading the Futures Forex and
crypto sounds like you actually make
more money now on your own rather than
back then as a prop Trader so so maybe
could you maybe walk you walk me through
some of the the trades or Investments
that you took right previously they know
that led to this this amount of money
that you have made okay when I was in
the prop desk I was there for 5 years in
total I made about 1.2 million
of which I take half so you CH 2.4 like
you calculate the 50% maybe the revenue
is 2 point something because you know
our margin is actually when we are doing
a shorter time frame you could be making
3,000 but actually your net profit is uh
1,000 because all the commission right
probably I made like two three but the
net profit is about 1.2 then of course
the 1.2 you you need to speed the
company 50/50 all right yeah so on on
paper I probably take home a 5
600 by yeah even though I maybe make two
two million or more of course all this
cost the bail along the way okay yeah so
that was the first five years after I
left the desk I of course I don't have
to pay the cut anymore and I was doing
on my own and that was also during the
time in 2016 when the crypto Market
start to be awakened right and I got
friends who a lot of friends and even
prop Des Traders I don't a lot of Pop
Traders like crypto Market they kind of
speculation or drive speculation and
that kind of thing you can't find in in
the Futures Market you found in uh
crypto so that was when I shift I
started shift bit I bit slowly to crypto
and I realiz that is and my first three
months of trading crypto right doing
swing trade I turn like I started with
like 30 40,000 I turn into 200,000 and I
was like oh
that's like everything I buy is like
boom multi multi back and that was like
I and I can sense that the the wave is
coming that was I position more towards
uh
crypto and good thing is luckily I have
the background in trading so I can
roughly see that where's the entry point
exit point do some risk management I
didn't really get burn out uh when
market crash fortunately in the last few
cycle uh but I always tell myself that
it may not last that's why I still do uh
trade a lot of
stocks I try to balance both sides I
still trade Hong Kong stocks US Stocks
crypto as well when I see that crypto
Market is going down I will trade more
US Stocks I see the market crypto Market
is going to boom I will trade more
crypto so that this is the like two
asset class I I I manage yeah okay and
then and then like in the after I joined
the after I left the prop Des I made
about $10 million in crypto was it more
of a from investing or more of position
trading I think a combination of both
sometimes I may enter Bas on
investment right but when I exit is
really 100% pure based on technicals
okay so even if I like the token like
Bitcoin or ethereum when I see the
pattern bearish pattern forming
manipulation pattern forming I may exit
before my intended target I always tell
my students like Bitcoin my target
is uh 200,000
but why do I sell when last time it was
20,000 why why do I sell when it was
like
70 over th000 recently because I saw the
kind of uh pattern there like bull trap
uh bearish pattern so sometimes you have
the fundamental Target but your my
technical sense will override the
fundamentals okay and you probably look
to reenter maybe at a later time at a y
better like like now okay okay so we'll
get to crypto shortly a lot to talk
about it over there as well but let me
back to trading for well what are some
maybe let's say someone who wants to get
started in trading what what advice
would you give to them or what will you
give your 21y old self when you know
when you wanted to trade back there I
think it's important to have a low
maintenance lifestyle you must be able
to sustain and cannot have too much
worry that you need to pay a lot of
bills and there's a lot sacrifice to be
made I mean you cannot
be you you just need to you must keep a
b minimum minimum lifestyle so that you
can free your mind to focus on Trading
I've seen some people where they have a
lot of Burden family burden financial
burden they have PID of car then they
have to trade is when they really come
focus
on yeah so don't just create a job just
to switch over entirely as well make
sure you have savings to tie you for at
least half a year and any trading books
that you usually recommend traders to go
and read I think one of a few books uh
that still stuck with me is big
performance
trading by
kongi wow that's a local book I have not
read that one okay so he he was with
Adam last time he trade mainly on the
Forex so he does the Forex cost you may
not find his book anymore in Kino or
popular I guess this out out but maybe
we can find
online pick performance trading by kongi
that's a trading psychology book uh is
it talks about Forex Trading but the
principles can be applied to where we
set class okay that has been still one
of the best book I I I read okay big
performance trading by K is he still
like you know actively trading around I
haven't like know heard of him from what
I know from Adam he really left
Singapore oh yeah
okay so yeah let's kind of move on to
the next section we talk about crypto
right so you have this course right
called the crypto current yeah so imag
how you got started in crypto was
because I think after prop trading it
kind of reminds me when you said that
the crypto markets reminds me of like
back then I think the K Futures before
the El go coming it seems like the
market were very similar like you know
it's not so sophisticated right big
comboy yeah which is what crypto was
like in 2016 2017 yeah so okay so you so
so there are like so many crypto tokens
being launch right so how do you then
know go about deciding you know which
are the ones that are worth investing
and which are the ones that just stay
away better okay in crypto we always say
that uh we go we see what drives the
narrative so I don't really have a maybe
this season I could be metaverse the
next season could be AI then maybe next
season could be rwa real war as set so I
try to be at a going before the
narrative starts so that's a key
question how do you know a narrative
going to start so there always have this
so- called Theory every do has his day
when something is too is in the top is
the top of the town I don't touch one so
like now popular AI real asset or memes
you you will not tou on this like you
tell me like like I think last few weeks
meme coins was pumping or what I was I
will not touch if because the real money
is made before the attention come in
when something comes in right you need
to have that resilience to stay away
then you need to look the best you can
do is to look out for the next one
because after the mem there will be
something there will always be something
it's just in the stock market as well
right uh previously was like I think
many years ago was like Mary Jenna stock
cannabis stocks and then there was like
EV and then metaverse then now ai but
all you you realize all after that after
that after maybe after a few years it
will come back so every Market has a
team but the team cycle in crypto is
faster the cycle change very like maybe
this few months metav next few months AI
but but stock market maybe take one year
to to realize that team so crypto is a
much faster game in my view which is
good if you are in really into
speculation you want something fast then
so what how I look out for narrative is
I will see what's happening in the last
half a year one year and if these are
them that's really came about in the
last half a year to one year then I will
not touch I position more in the teams
that are still under
radar so those tokens that under R I'm
guessing the their price be like just
just consolidating very like a ER
patient at almost they're not really
moving much they go for the leaders
sometimes the people have to go for the
like
the the best is always go for the the
top the top three or top five of that
leader in the category then watch for
the the any bullish
signal yeah so is there like a tool or
screener that can help you screen for
such tokens that you're looking for
that's you know under the radar and then
they are still like the the leaders of
that that category age I don't really
use a screener but I use like coin Geo
and then you know like when you look at
certain tokens they they do categorize
them like say this is uh decentralized
exchange then you just click inside then
you see the they are sort out based on
the biggest market cap to lowest market
cap they just focus on the first five
okay see then you I go into a chart one
by one to see if there's a setup okay
and then if I buy I'll just tell myself
that I have something in this category
then I want something in that category
then you in your portfolio you can have
different teams that you're going for
does the fun do you take into account
the fundamental of the tokens like you
know the tokenomics you know the team
behind it or just more of a technical
play um usually like the first the top
five will naturally be the better the
the ones with better fundamentals in the
category the natural natural selection
really right is really done I but I look
out for R Flex like is the team
Anonymous I have a few occasions where I
remember even some of my friends got
into projects where team can give 1,000
excuses to be anonymous they say that
they are from China they not they want
to reveiew themselves because they SK
China government go after them 1,000 one
excuse the one lesson I learned don't
care what is the excuse as long as they
are Anonymous is one major reflect
except for Bitcoin Bitcoin is anonymous
but Bitcoin is a different is a
different use case it's decentralized
and it's been proven there's no project
to be done Bitcoin has no road map the
road map is over but for projects that
are asking for your money and their roap
is not
done yeah and they Anonymous some more
it's not proven yet okay so you okay so
then after when it comes to technicals
again you can use your similar setups
which you Shar like you know the B buot
trap to you know get an entry to go long
stop so a lot of the principles they sh
is actually very applicable to the other
markets out there yeah corre so what are
some of the maybe upcoming trends that
you're seeing in the crypto space right
now
I think AI will come back okay the
reason is because in the stock market uh
AI narative is still not yet de in my
view uh you see Nidia is still alltime
high even though it retraced a little
bit and it's like the driving stock for
or sector for the entire stock
market in fact I think I one of Adam's
video like AI stocks is the one that
drive S&P 500 to alltime high so if
there's true right then even though
crypto Market AI crypto came down which
they did in the last few months since
March they Dr about 80 90% most of them
I do see that there could be a
convergence back that mean some of the
crypto uh
AI tokens may may do a catch up bounce
back they drop mainly because of the
overall mro environment in crypto but
the team is still there in the stock
market so the AI team is is still not
yet did unlike last time when the
metaverse right uh when the metaverse
height comes in a lot meta stock like Ro
blocks all these kind of stock right
they
actually uh went up together with crypto
not crypto metav stock crypto metaverse
coins and then they die together and
that's where the wave gone but this time
out the in the stock market the crypto I
mean the the AI stocks are still holding
that's why there's still a chance for
crypto AI to to ready so crypto is kind
of like taking lead from the traditional
stock market as long as the traditional
stock market the height is still there
there a good chance crypto could you
know come back from the date and you
know catch up with it correct all right
yeah makes a lot of sense okay so if you
don't mind sharing you know what are
some of the coins that you're holding
now right and and why you're holding
them okay for about uh since March right
I position more into big caps for
stability so how you define a big cap
for yourself okay uh actually much I
catch about half of my portfolio and I
position more towards big caps like
Bitcoin ethereum xrp these are the
safest picks in my view and then I still
hold on to like other smaller tokens
like uh larine which has dropped like 80
90% just a very small portion I catch
out 80% of it I'm still looking to go
back in okay because it is uh is backed
by a lot of big players like coinbase
Venture all these are inside I think
cool coin also inside
yeah okay just a quick one do you know
that you can download the transcript of
this episode this way you can easily
recap the lessons and insights of this
episode without having to listen to it
again and that's not all because you can
also download the transcripts of all my
past episodes and quickly catch up on
what you've missed so if you're
interested go down to roto.com
/script script is spelled as s c r i p
TT so once again it's rain.com
/script now back to the show so what's
your take on like like like this cycle
do you think it's the top already in or
is there still you know more room to
grow for next six to 12 months I mean
more room for price to go up higher from
what I see right now uh the the price
action of Bitcoin is on the high time
frame they does a very big bull trap
okay he retested the alltime highest
Ming there okay and the last few weeks
or month they couldn't hold above so we
we try to kind hold above right High
chance it may R Trace back which is
doing it at the at this at the moment
right now so I suppose it may drop back
towards 50k level and this drop the the
thing is that I think if you're holding
on to bitcoin ethereum you should there
if you have a longer time Horizon it
should be okay but because of the drop
in Bitcoin ethereum right the odds will
suffer further because usually liquidity
gets stuck off them faster than the big
caps that's why even in the that's why
how crypto Traders position themselves
doing the bare Market is not really to
sell of everything yes you can cash out
but after you cash out you reposition to
big
caps there that's is like the the the
player okay yeah then like like Bitcoin
E I guess you do believe in the
fundamental or the utility behind this
this two tokens or what's your take on
on bitcoin maybe long term I do have I
maintain my Target price of 200k and
above what's the reason for like like
200k I I did a uh valuation comparison
with gold okay so Bitcoin is created to
disrupt a go so that's why you use it as
a
comparable so I think if Bitcoin hit
about
200k Bitcoin hit about
200k uh price point right that would be
about
30% of goal 20 30% of goal if I'm not
wrong based on my last
calculation so there's still a long way
to go actually if you were to replace
gold
eventually then like ethereum will be
comparable to Microsoft because ethereum
is like the micro like the operating
system for crypto Microsoft is like the
operating system for the real
world so that's how I compare them I I
have my I compare them with the
real stocks ah okay are there any like
maybe smaller alt coins that you see
that there's a real world utility like
you know solving a problem in the real
world which you find that yeah there's
certain
uh prospects in these tokens I think
next one will be xrp oh Ripple reple
okay yeah actually I think I read
somewhere you had a 40x investment in in
Ripper
right R is one of my like bigger wins uh
back in 2016 could you walk me through
maybe that that that trade or investment
that you took you know how did that come
about I remember when I was it I I went
to reservice during the time and one my
very good friend he's a Visionary I once
I I have to say he's he's someone he he
doesn't come from a very big like very
glamorous copy background but he's
someone he's a big thinker back in 2016
where everyone was like still don't
trust crypto all this right he he
actually one day is doing I remember in
cam he actually told me this set us down
a few of us down and say bro I don't
listen to me there's this
token you must go and take a look this
thing called xrp this will changed the
world and I look up to him because he's
the he's our CSM okay yeah so and I know
that he's uh he he's someone who do due
diligence
on right and that's why I'm going to
take a look and I find that wow actually
the potential is huge is disrupting the
the way no uh remittance company Banks
going to they have the nostril account
right they have to park money here and
there and then XR going disrup all these
liquidity
pools this is going to be a game changer
right because trillions of dollars are
moving every day xrp just need to take
like 10% Swift of what Swift is moving
and it will be a billion dollar crypto
and with that conviction during the time
that was that was when I I remember for
like a good one month every day I go
inside coinbase right I buy to The Mex
you mean there a there's a limit you can
buy each day back then yes I think like
one day maximum a$ few hundred only then
you refresh by so okay so every day buy
buy Max Max Max then you have to use Bor
Bor friend um account father mother
account to
buy so was was technical involved back
then when you're buying it's more like
fundamental I think he going to dis let
me just buy this one was purely uh
fundamentals okay you didn't care about
technicals you just because it was so
the chy in my view what was the price
back then when you were buying Every Day
0.0000 Z something I think 4 Z three Z 4
Z okay and let's say you buy then C back
so small the price can just 40 50% this
your conviction still still remain when
you know such draw down occurs okay I
have to admit that during the time I
didn't really I thought myself I would
lose everything oh that's your mindset
you had already okay either Zer or do
the
moon yeah hit
uh and also I trust my friend he cuz he
has a lot like during the financial
crisis he bought one stop he put 3,000
and he turn into
200,000 I I so he he's the kind that he
has his own way of thinking and he he
his story also inspire me so I look up
to him a lot yeah that's amazing he's a
very different view of the world one
like he don't really go by the normal
way and he has always I not asking for
his
views and every time we meet up for
coffee he always share with us like
what is the key things that he's looking
up for and he's he's now like uh semi-
retired yeah great great so okay moving
on right so let's maybe jump a little
bit and move on talk about the education
part because I I I I believe you also
have a education business right you know
xspy Trader so how did that come about
so uh 2016 after I left and I was given
Opportunity by Adam right I was actually
one of Adam's uh students as well then I
told Adam about this ad asked me like
what I do in the prop des and I iing
time I should share him that uh like why
I told you like things that we look out
for what kind of strategy we use in the
prop des and he told me it's very
interest something very interesting why
not you do a
c right
and I'm sure a lot of people want to
attend even him himself I still remember
during the time Adam my first course
that I
conducted uh actually I I personally
have reservation so when I when I
started I was like my last time my
mindset not very strong my mindset not
very strong so I was like will people
listen to
me early
30s but Adam is the kind that you know
everything is possible he actually
remember him doing telling me
this uh telling me this it doesn't
matter how old you are you you got the
skill the substance carity and then was
like okay then I need to give value to
people who actually uh learn trading
from from our course I remember I do the
course and Adam personally attended for
four days wow and it's not like he come
and go know he sat there in the morning
until the the last day and what his
secretary actually told one of them one
of the directors told me that he asked
his secretary to block out the four days
the time he was flying like one week
like I heard he was flying like three
four times around the region but he
block out the Friday Saturday Sunday
Monday just to attend the course and
that was to me a super good great honor
cuz I learned a lot from him I look up
to him a lot that was how I started and
after the first CL I was like he
actually I enjoy doing it then that was
when I have arrangement with Adam to
come back to conduct it every three
months three to four months I see but
right now is it more of back then was
physical but right now is it still
physical or is it more of like Zoom
really now we do uh during Co and until
now we do more on Zoom ready because now
we have international students who
cannot attend physically okay yeah but
before that was physical and back then
when you have your first batch of
student you have to create a materials
from scratch and then someone who's a
Trader now becoming educator you know
how is that transition like for you how
do you even get your materials really
how do you even know what should you say
what shouldn't you say in your teaching
materials I just do what I think as a
student I want to see I always ask
myself when I do uh my C material if I'm
a new Trader what I want
want I don't want to have all the like
Theory right I want give me the chart
the strategy show me the chart and where
you enter and stop loss so when I out my
cost my cost manual like most of it is
charts and very little Theory because I
know people don't want you can talk all
the theory but in theend the back of the
mind is tell me where to buy you're
right where to put the stop loss we want
scenario take profit then different
scenarios that's how my my Approach when
I conducted the do the C manual and of
course Adam gave a lot of advice like
time he would tell me hey too
complicated this one like why you like
too long winded all this then uh I will
change then then some you may tell me
like maybe you can express it different
way cuz sometimes like you know like cup
a glass half full half empty in
sometimes you can say it's half empty
you say in other way is simpler So Adam
is a he's someone who can break down
complicated concept into something
simple and I learned a lot from him on
on on this
education and he always tell us that
some education is not just about
delivery of the content because as a
teacher as a content creator you also
need to entertain yeah right I mean
content anyone can go and F but
sometimes people want that
entertain I always I train my students I
do relate to them like my experience the
prop t know some
stories make it more interesting and
more they can relate yeah yeah they have
a for they call entainment a teaching
plus entertainment you know combined
together so you have four days of
teaching so maybe you can walk me
through briefly what is covered in each
of the four days like four days like
most people think it's a full day if I'm
not wrong right like what 9 to six that
kind of hours so now uh it's over two
weekends now so Saturday Sunday Saturday
Sunday are we personally conducting the
four days uh is from 10 a.m. Singapore
time to 3:30 p.m. Singapore time okay
yeah over Zoom but we we have a one uh
sorry two half an hour break in between
lunch break okay for lunch break for all
four days is the same yep okay so I'm
guessing it's going to be like day one
will'll be like covering the basics the
foundations corre cover the strategies
and there risk management the psychology
so all in all about four days so first
weekend will be more on like the
introduction and then we'll cover just
one strategy and then do we cover
screening yeah enough to for to get
started uh so the one week break is
actually for them to catch up on the
content meaning those who didn't manage
to attend life they can catch up on I
like the first weekend right the things
that we cover let them digest during the
week uh the one week okay because on the
next week Saturday is more on strategy
and usually students who are very new
they may struggle on the on the
strategies uh
day that's why I always say that the one
week is foring to catch up then that's
where we find that it's much better
based on our feedback for most students
and when I go to strategy I can skip a
bit of the basic really right I go
straight to the charts and I'll just
tell them like in this kind of
scenario the ex the confirmation signal
this are buy and sell all this kind of
thing we can just go straight to that
without going too much back and forth on
the basic anymore okay yeah so for this
one you say you with Adam to help
promote the business so how is the
marketing done is it like handled
entirely by that team or do you have any
marketing that you do on your own as
well yeah so uh I don't do I don't
really do the marketing on my own except
creating the uh marketing uh V uh videos
right uh so marketing site like what you
see in social media YouTube Facebook is
done by Adam s okay and you prefer it
this way like you don't have any plans
maybe set up your own YouTube channel
your own of telegram channel to to kind
of like get more reach organically uh I
I thought of it before but I find that
it could be a very tedious process I
want to focus more on trading side makes
sense it's like I'm trading both stocks
and crypto and I need to coach my
students if I have to go and focus on
there's just too many things on the
plate and one of them was cice on so my
my passion is still more mostly on on
trading in fact I still trade very
actively even to today so I I still want
to focus on this like trading side yeah
and then now that you know you're no
longer with your your peers in prop
trading how do you get this kind of like
Community or camarad that you used to
have whereas now you're trading
independently on your own I think
there's two there's okay there's two
groups I I I get this kind of vibe from
like uh same for Adam like when we meet
up I can tell our whole conversation
doing lunch or dinner right it's all
about trading
investment right the whole doing lunch
is all about it which is our passion
then we can get ideas like what Adam
would share about what he's what he see
what's his view on the last few months
right or upcoming what do you think he
thinks is going to matter to the markets
you know or share and that's where we
learn from each other and also some we
have
certain uh struggles we also share each
other then of course Adam is the big
brother in my view so if any issues like
I will always ask him how do you deal
with with it you know that's the way I I
actually learn also like Adam when you
when you face this of
scenario how do you deal with it yeah I
now ask I'll ask him he always give a
good advice through his experience then
another is my students in the community
I do a money Gathering every month
physical Zoom or Zoom uh Zoom also okay
in fact I can tell you most of the time
like last time I when I'm own right I'm
alone I need to screen on my own like f
opportunity I see the world maybe this
in a very narrow way okay but when I
when in my community Sometimes some of
them may be exposed to different sector
then during the Gathering they may ask
me about stocks that is from another
world how about this token or crypto to
or how about this stock that is
sometimes I I I get ideas from there in
fact doing my gathering right I have a
piece of paper my stent ask about stock
I go I see straight away I like I write
down first
I'm learning and teaching at the same
time that's why I got my ideas and some
of in fact I think most nowadays most of
stock I enter is what I share in
gathering or what I what I share my uh
what my student had Shar with me before
so a win win for both
both and also I think I noticed on the
website you have this uh price action
manipulation course which has two parts
which are sold separately so I'm curious
why not sell it like like part one part
two together bundle it as as one rather
than you know separate like level one
level
two uh is it's actually sold in P
profits.com website right for the price
section manipulation cost level one I
saw yes so uh students can purchase as a
bundle or alakat okay level one or level
two okay you need to you need to have
level one before you can enroll to level
two okay so level one actually is enough
to for you to get started because we
teach you the basic and then uh
screening executions and
two strategy and risk management you can
get started on without level two but if
you want to know how to tackle different
scenario because in the market there's
sideways pattern uptrend downtrend
continuation look for ultimate tops
ultimate bottoms and sculping I Do cover
more on that on level two in level two
yeah and other different strategies also
okay
so level one is independent on its own
but level two is more the advanced stuff
if people want to cover different Market
environment situations okay yeah okay
and also curious to to to hear you know
what why do you then want to teach right
when you clearly have enough to to
retire so for me personally it's more of
like number one I make more money my
teaching honestly number two is
diversification and number three is uh
it was very fun actually when we
engaging with students and doing videos
so but curious to hear your point of
view for yourself yes uh initially I
want I to me I I didn't really talk too
much about money with Adam at the start
in fact I think we never brought up
about the money I didn't even know how
much I will I will get I was just say at
the start uh I'll just do all passion
how much I get paid doesn't matter up to
doday I never talk to Adam about what's
the cut I never argue like I must get
this person I never talk about that it
just come naturally based on industry
standard and I always tell myself that I
cannot focus just on
the education part right for
Revenue I focus more on the trading side
so of course if I were to do this I
I it has to has to be a business that is
profitable for Adam and also uh for
myself for my time right but I'm not
going just relying just on this because
I think that if if I Rely just on the
education part for survival right it may
cill my passion in trading entirely
you see I may not uh I may not hold my
skill set
as as uh profoundly as if I were to just
focus on teaching because your time will
be diluted between education and trading
yeah so towards the now we can move on
to the closing SE session I think I read
this somewhere again Adam pretty much I
think thinks very highly of you so he
say something like you know you've built
a $15 million property portfolio with
your trading profits so how do you then
go about you know building your own
property portfolio actually start off
with this thing Adam always say like in
education the tough part is not to get
bought in education the tough part is
not to get bought because you're
repeating the same thing oh okay
sometimes you can repeat the same answer
right and I as over the years uh I have
I have a passion on property as well
right I in fact I have I license CA
license mean your Property agent that
license it yeah but I don't practice on
you will never find any any any my face
anywhere or any transaction yeah even my
own I buy my own house I don't get
anybody I mean I don't do myself you get
someone else to help facilitate yeah
okay so it's just our passion I just
want to learn more because I think it's
a big ticket item so I I want to know I
don't just everything delegate but I
still need an agent to execute but I
want to know what's happening so I
bought more I bought my properties
during covid where I see the opportunity
and I was inspired by my former boss as
well which is it the one at trading or
the one that uh trading trading so he he
built up a sizable property portfolio as
well and it was also very inspiring you
say using the trailer mindset also like
he bought I think landed properties Shop
houses during uh the financial crisis
and he share with us like casually last
night I remember like he bought
something for like 600,000 the hdb shop
now it's worth 2 million well the kind
of story know really inspire you know
and then then he he's the kind that uh
will humble you or so he will tell you
like we make money invest in property
don't anyhow spend this kind so I
learned that kind of values from him
also so when opportunity came in
2020 right the
crisis uh I actually went in to buy uh
two Shop houses so it's currently tented
out as a site as a site business I
actually operate one of the shop I'm
operating a Hoster just started but uh
I'm I'm just overseeing everything so I
just leave it for for investment so you
collect the the year plus capital
appreciation for the the shop house yes
yeah so do you have to be the one
managing the tenants you know and stuff
like that all the drafting of all the
agreements yeah so fortunately I got the
experience in uh real estate so uh my
tenants direct to me what does direct to
you mean that means they they if there's
any like tency agreement I do myself on
I dro the the deny agreement for them to
sign oh you don't drop it up okay yeah I
I drop it I don't go to like agent or
let's say there's some issues with the
the roof or anything right they come
directly to me and then my my dad is a a
contractor so it's very easy the handy
man just call because I feel that if you
have go to agent like well the agent to
go and find contractor they give code
you going and tell agent then don't way
the agent going tell the T then you
always do that kind
of misom delay some just call me
directly I just we I'll just set it sh
we but why Shop houses instead of like
other type of of properties out there
during Co I remember I read article you
know Bitcoin is scarce 21 million
Bitcoin right and the scarcity is the
reason why uh it is so available so I
saw article I was like this is like
Bitcoin also
like uh Heritage Shop houses commercial
Shop houses they are there's only like
6,000 in Singapore government cannot
build more they conserve most of them
are
conserve uh conserve the the conserve
means are if today the government want
to tear down is not so easy they have to
go through it's not like the SLA issue
you a directive land acquisition act and
then they can just take it it's a law
that they cannot take on actually even
if they don't be m that to build around
it wow powerful yeah because some of
it's like pre-wall oh okay so it's it's
it's like a it's a property and also a
an am I to say like along J notice Shop
houses some the design very very similar
I guess those those are what I mean by
the preserved Shop houses correct so I
have one shop hous in jet Ted to a pet
shop yeah is I think it's built pre- War
also and I don't know how he survived uh
after the war but the building still
there so there's the kind of like vibe
that the vibe you know that a lot of
investors want to buy this as a asset
okay and you can rent it out for a
renter or you can even choose to stay if
you want to uh if it's a commercial full
commercial you can't really take it as a
residential but you want to stay is okay
up to you yeah okay you're actually
someone who's actually quite quite
amazing you very open mind you know you
willing to know go into crypto or
trading now you know property investment
and yeah I think I think open-mindedness
really brought you to very you know far
places right and you know of course
clearly achieving the success you have
today so so what are you excited about
right now you know personally or
professionally I would like to continue
to do my education part of the business
and moving forward I look forward to
getting my my my house soon I bought a
place at AMU so that was I think the
next milestone for me
personally and of course to start a
by next year right some that's a game
changer
man so so I'm I'm curious so let's say
know you have of course a a huge Lum
some of money how do you then allocate
decide okay this one goes to trading
this one goes to property you know
because some people they diversify so
what's like a percentage that you are
comfortable with with your managing of
your
money for trading site I I icate about
uh $1 million I think that's a
comfortable range and whenever I make
money from Trading
uh I would just take away anything
beyond that one M mark because I I don't
need too much to engage the market and I
think that will be beyond my comfort
zone also the dollar amount of money
that's being deployed deployed okay so
when if I make money I will like doing
Co when I make I just cash out okay and
just keep that size at one millon so I I
constantly know that no I I lock in the
profit so actually whatever is in my
portfolio right now is All Pure profit M
so in other words actually you can
actually make more money in terms of
like percentage return because trading
is definitely more than I think property
but because of I guess being comfortable
with you know what's at risk in the
market you rather choose to make less
but still sleep better at night that's
the that's what you're saying but I
would say that it is still when when I
see a great opportunity I can I
can
soall uh go in much bigger if I want to
when the opportunity arise like similar
for crypto if I if I really see
everything bottom out and things is
going to move up soon in my view right I
will I will still go in a much bigger
size is there like maybe like a
percentage where you feel that that's
like your heart start limit like maybe
not more than I don't know 50% of your
wealth in the financial markets do you
have like certain percentage in mind
that you your your heart stop limit
currently would say that like property
is about 80 over per of my net worth
less than 20% is in uh crypto to and
also stocks among them I do like I don't
go Beyond 20% in the portfolio for every
big even for a big position so there is
my my H stop if it's uh if my portfolio
is about 500,000 then the stop loss for
that particular position if I really re
big is about 50 to 100K
okay crypto sometimes can yeah crypto
also like if I go into a certain
position also about 50 100K per position
so at this stage you it's to be have the
case of let's say I know 40 50% in
property then the remaining 40 50% in
the financial markets there'll be too
too much for for for you at this stage
actually also because the naturally the
property valuation move up and because
it's leverage instrument all right but
to me I always I don't see them as
together I always see them as separate I
focus on the the portfolio in stocks and
crypto and at any point time if the
opportunity is there's a lot of
opportunity then of course I MA dra my
using my attach to P in
more uh and because it's so even though
I got one mil but it can also be leverag
if I want to True with within the
account and I'm account person who I
like to go for small re big gain yeah
calculated re small re and then go for
big gains so I don't really need that I
can I can just use 200k to make one or
two Mill that was how I I I started also
like crypto 40K and then turn two into 2
millon and then over the years I started
to to build it
up yeah cuz I also have this this taugh
myself cuz I I don't have I'm besides
this this this uh flat right I don't
have any other property so a lot of my
money is actually in the financial
markets trading investing so I'm
thinking you know I might need to
diversify away instead of having so much
of my ex in that in that one instrument
so so that's why I ask you the question
how were you going about you know
managing a money across these different
asset classes yeah I think the biggest
risk to me is one black one youen on and
then and you know when black on even
because the correlation of markets can
just all go to one I'm like I'll be
screwed big time like you know when that
happen so so yeah I need to think about
it
myself so what does your your your daily
routine look like right now daily
routine uh I trade mainly the US market
so the US timing hasle we later we 2 or
3:00 and I sleep 2 3:00 a.m. you
mean then I get active at night uh from
900 p.m. onwards
before the opening you already there
your desk usually n yeah just half an
hour before but before that will be more
of administrative work and sometimes do
some marketing work for uh for the C and
doing my screening and I also learned
this lesson when I when about this like
most of the work is done not when you're
are trading when you're trading you
cannot thing on I don't know whether
it's true but when I trade out it's
really just applying applying and
thinking a bit different like when you
because when when the market is closed
you off a computer and then you bring
out the chart everything become a stand
still that's where you look at it you
can look at it very differently but when
the chart is moving you just in the
action you're not
really understanding like you're just
really to just apply only so I think a
lot of work is done Beyond before and
after trading so for me personally even
though Market I start active on actively
monary Market at
before that I'm doing a lot of screening
on my own I screen the market every day
I screen like most of the time it's
screening and you can tell screening
take a lot of work like uh even though
time Gathering I get some ideas but on
my own I still screen the US Market Hong
Kong market and also crypto market and I
don't really have a I do I use screener
but screener is not 100% you still need
to manually go and see whether is ready
or not then I'll mark it down or have a
notebook to mark it down all this and
and some that I do share my students as
well but for crypto it's mostly
manual US Stocks I got scripts for my
students the scanning script but crypto
I need to one by one go inside and then
see the different the the weekly time
frame or sometimes the monthly time
frame and then I need to when I go into
a certain crypto I need to go and see
the fundamentals like get a sense of
whether it's a there's a red flag
there so that was more of tedious
process yeah so that's how what I do day
today
mostly and for your stock screener why
couldn't like the screener maybe give
you exactly what you want whereas you
still need to go another layer deep to
fil out what screener gives you screener
can only screen for open H close right
open H close and if you're looking for
the specific bar formation but if you're
looking at let's say uh to check for
previous swing low and then you want
that kind of flash down for example we
are able to do it but there are certain
scenario that you will still miss
because Market is dynamic sometime you
say you want that swing low then it
could be it could be in this manner then
some it could be like this then go up or
you want to flash something you could go
up first then flash so you need a bit of
like machine learning going on there
it's not like a just checking for open H
close and and some of my strategy
require a bit of like judgment call also
uh you need to visually see it then you
need to be able to draw that wave
pattern but how do you code to tell the
scen Winer to see that wave pattern so
that's the challenge Al my one of my
coaches Richard tried to do that also uh
the best you can do is to short list the
results then you still have to manually
go and check one by one because
sometimes they are not what you want and
then they not ready yet they always tell
my students sometimes you screen is not
for today it's for maybe the next few
days or next week like some of my traes
that took today is what I screen yester
uh yesterday or last week so it's a
homework that it's continuous homework
that you have to do is there any chance
that like one day you will actually
fully systemize this entire strategy or
system that you have so that you know it
can kind of like run much more
automatically I wish there's a there
there's is there's a possibility to do
something like that like there's a
machine learning and then you can do
back testing and then you can really
just click the button and then you can
auto run by itself but I've not found
anyone able to do that okay all right
and maybe just one last technical
question so we talk quite a bit about
the The Flash you know boo and bear trap
so but the flush of course there's many
variations some could be break then
immediately Zoom reverse some could be
break then three four candles down then
reverse and some could be break you know
down for very long maybe one to week 10
suddenly reverse what's your take on all
these different types of variations of
the you know the flush so uh initially
when I when I qued cost I actually
Define them specifically what's a
there's a difference between a flash
down and a flash down bar a flash down
bar is definitely a flash down but a
flash down may not be a flash down bar
because a flash down can just be small
bars that is going down
rapidly there may not be a big great bar
we we still call it a flash down but
flash down bar means the weight bar is
outt standing in range so I Define that
specifically for my student
so if you see either one of these is
still bearish it still shows that
there's rapid price movement down yeah
so we definely very clearly and then in
some of strategy we are looking for uh
flash down flash down bar yeah Al
sometimes you might look for a series of
bar and sometimes you might look for
just one big great bar down correct okay
then what about the the reversal does it
matter whether it's like a f candle
reversal back up above support or you're
looking for like a big green candle one
two candle back up above support in
terms of maybe the reliability of the
signal okay so I I I think I understand
what I mean like after hit the support
then reverse right do a b trap then when
you reverse the the bullish bar has to
close above the support of course like
in your scenario if it close too high up
then this what we call two white white w
i d e two white so we have a entry rule
it is two white two white means that
your entry and your stop loss is more
than the current
ATR let's say the current ATR there's
this indicator called the ATR average
true range indicator it is $1 currently
at $1 and then let's say your green bar
move up appear and then your you want to
enter when the green bar close and then
your stop loss the distance between
entry and stop loss is let's say $2 so
$2 versus your current at or $1 right is
is what we call two white because it's
more than your current ATR so in that
scenario my students either wait for it
to retrace back below the one
Mark or they just don't take any don't
don't chase okay because sometimes you
if you if the the bar the Big Green B
came out right and then you still on
enter right what happen is that either
you tighten up your stop
loss or you aim much higher and most of
the time right when if you still
maintain your stop loss and the big
green bar come out you still enter right
your take profit Target could be very
high up and this is the instances where
a lot of Traders May will always say
that uh I wait too long never hit Target
then they come back down because they
they overpay for the trade we use the
word
overpay all right so is there anything
that you know you wish to add right you
know in today's show that we didn't have
a chance to talk about
earlier I think we mostly covered part
and it brings me back to
Memories when I was in the in the prop
Des is I still cherish those
moments maybe you can share like I think
a lot of people want to like to ask like
what's my biggest draw
down how I handle
it uh be beyond the kind of success
story right I think one of the biggest
draw down I have when was when I was in
the prop desk I remember they was doing
non fund pay you know we trade the what
we call the data right and then the
market go
against I think during a time that was a
very bullish data then naturally is to
long is to is to go long so it was a
very bullish
data but I don't know why the mark so we
I went in go to go long it was bullish
data some job job job uh the non pay was
positive I things so I went in but
Market keep going down he keep going
down and I just don't
believe W data boomber data damn good do
buy some more aage but keep going down
but and I still don't believe how can it
go down 100 points no way man they just
keep buying by by then I was down about
10,000 damn matter of minutes seconds I
think within like two two two
minutes yeah so my my my daily draw down
during the time I was a bit uh in two
three years in the desk I think my daily
draw down was like 20K given to me and I
don't believe in the market came going
down well suddenly right you were so
happy for your
whole real the reality struck
holy what did I get myself into
then things get worse then become like
20K no like when in in the in the pop
desk we have a r manager so he STI
across me I still remember he he he gave
this
signal this is cut you cut asking me to
cut cost 20K so because they they don't
they don't press the button to cut for
you you have to cut yourself but they'll
give you a signal I know I hit my res
liit and
I signal that I need I need to have more
limits that means uh buffer that mean I
want to continue it's like you want to
have more leeway so I think he call my
boss and then give me more leeway so I
can go beyond 20K for the time being and
for after a while the market did reverse
back but came back
down holy I was like long no know
how many Futures then
well then they he almost like 30k the
moment I cut and and then know then I
see the
signal me I'm dead this signal I cut you
cannot already I cut after I cut the
whole thing
reversed oh my w that
was I lost what I made in the last one
man plus W in that few minutes that's
why sometimes when Trader tell me like
they they lose
like a day lose what they make a few
days ago they have not don't understand
what is really like sometimes in in in
the in the in the desk I I it's not just
happened to me happen to some Traders as
well even good Traders sometimes and I
use the word t know that use T right I I
also T during time W cut the whole thing
go up well for the day I cannot TR
anymore I I I sto but after I go back
home I I I do a AR with myself I go back
to the price action everything and I ask
myself why am I stubbornly long and I
learned a a very very valuable lesson
data bullish doesn't mean the market
must go up sometimes it came down
because people say it's price in you no
matter what you still need to look at
the price action and if Sunny something
turn turn against you right like very
bullish and things keep going against
you you just need to cut first don't
question the market that's one key
lesson I learned but fortunately in
enough within the next one two weeks I
may
back so even though I lose 30 I may like
30 40 right but even though it's not
glamorous but it is a great one of the
greatest lesson I learned I still like I
cherish the lesson more than the the
money that's that's that's made yeah the
lesson is to trust the price not the
data yes I learn it a hard hard way I
used to keep saying that but you never
know until you really
went through that thing and then you
know how hard it is to build back that
the
capital and would yeah when you say you
you sold at the low that thing rebound
the thing rebound is it because you
cover your your trade or is it because
it's meant to rebound at Point time
really and after I see is uh it does a
bad
travel and I cut exactly at the
low holy
and when you do your areview you
print and you're looking through the
charts and then try to review on it is
it oh yeah this also one thing I told my
students last time even though I I never
splush on anything right I I a very
maintenance size St but I have a printer
and I always every month I spend a few
hundred on the printer in every day
after I go at the end of the trading
session I print out all the
charts SMP NASDAQ Dow Jones n gold
silver euro dollar everything I print
out color I want to color because I want
to see like as if I'm looking at the
screen then I pin out and then I'll go
back home for the day at stapler then I
will just whether I watching TV or going
out eating or what I'll just I I I stay
at the thing and look for pattern a
circle pattern and I'll just draw if I
enter here where I be able to take
profit and I'll just see oh this pattern
I see very familiar keep repeating
itself this something this boot trap
more poent or this B trap more poent
what happened before the B trap that
will make it more poent this buol trp
they I look out for this kind of
scenario and compare compare every day
so that's my homework that's why I say
trading the time you can't really think
you can't really do the kind analysis
you need to beyond that some Traders
they just call the computer go home but
actually close computer I was still I
know that I need to do a lot homework I
don't do because yesterday's lesson
right you don't you cannot go to waste
if you don't learn from yesterday what
happened right you will you will forget
in two days time because Market mov very
fast is it something that you still do
till today the
a today I don't uh because my set of
strategy that I created right has is
already fine tuned over the years really
so right now what I do is I just
visually see a lot uh I think it's a I
don't really do that print out the
charts anymore but whenever I see some
interesting setup I do print them and I
put it I'll put it one side first I'll
tell myself this could be my new
structure yeah but after a while I see
hey no these are not very powerful like
I don't think this is repeatable and
this is okay so actually what's a good
strategy let people ask a good strategy
is something repeatable right if it's
repeatable means you got H so that's
that's what I look look out for and the
reason why I thought about price action
manipulation because manipulation
pattern is very repeatable you can see
it almost on a daily basis and there's a
basis for it yeah so I I do look out for
this comp of patters and even though
it's not manipulation related sometimes
I also look out for it because sometimes
some I know some Shing strategy may not
be manipulation related it could be a
technical related I so I also look out
for that as well and let's say you
potentially identify a new setup
strategy pattern that you may want to
trade in the future how do you
then validate it to so oh yeah this one
really has an age in the markets do you
like do an impact testing or you kind of
like you have your own way of validating
it okay so what I do is I I will print
out the last if it's on a weekly
chart okay so last time I do I I when I
if it's on the sculping I'll print out
the last 90 days it's let's say the SW
swing trading weekly chart I ping out
the last five years then I will randomly
choose 10 20 stocks then I would pin out
already right then that's my homework
for the week then I'll just ask my okay
this is my pattern now I'll just circle
and I will be unbiased on that means I
don't like play cheat like oh I I give
chance no I be like a strict teacher
this one I enter okay it's a plus or
minus that means win or lose okay then
after that it's very manual one there a
lot a lot of I don't know how to do back
testing so I just manually do right then
I I will just put in the piece of paper
like I'm a teacher marking the paper
okay this one this stock last five years
plus four W 2 L 4 win 2 L okay then I do
everything I consol it in the simple
Excel then just calculate then if the
last five years I see that 60 70 wind
weight and I when I do my so called
manual analysis right I can see that he
always move at least one to two hour
right and I to me it's a good
strategy because it persist out
Randomness also because I randomly put
pick seven Ian 10 stocks and I I'm I'm
I'm biased in my
analysis speaks a lot boy work ethics
okay so one last thing where can the
audience find and connect with you I
think earlier you mentioned uh we'll put
your link right in the description below
right since uh you know it's better for
you that way I think Elson actually
prefers to be kind of low profile but
still there's a way to connect with him
we I'll put it in the description below
right if you want to connect with Elson
yeah you you guys can actually reach out
to me uh you can find me in my my
courses at prian profits.com
right you can you can find me Adam bang
the two of us are actually uh training
over there at pan profits Adam does more
on the investment side bang more on the
option side and for me it's more on the
the price action manipulation trading
side all right so thank you so much for
your time I appreciate you thanks V
thanks for having me in this interview
nice chatting with you hey hey what's up
my friend so just one thing before you
go do you know you can download the
transcript of this episode this way you
can easily recap the lessons and
insights of this episode without having
to listen to it again and that's not all
because you can also download the
transcripts of all the past episodes and
quickly catch up on what you've missed
so if you're interested to do that then
go down to roto.com
script script is spelled as s c r i PT
so once again it's reo.com SL script go
check it out and I'll talk to you soon
[Music]